<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Travian Guide</title>
    <link>http://www.travianguide.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Travian Guide</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.travianguide.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Travian Roman Guide</title>
      <link>http://www.travianguide.com/travian-roman-guide</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.travianguide.com/travian-roman-guide</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;#Tenants of Good Travian Roman Play&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read the guide about how to not be a farm.
Focus on farming all in-actives in range twice a day
Never leave your army sitting at home, an army at home goes to waste.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avoid fights with players who have army
Your goal is to only hit those who can’t defend themselves&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Never listen to IGM’s from your farms because they are your resource fields. Don’t destroy them.
Use diplomacy to work towards joining a decent alliance. Once you are accepted a real alliance your empire becomes much stronger.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remember, too many allies means less farms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your resources should never be empty while your at the computer, and your warehouse should never fill up while your away, if it does, make it bigger or play more often!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Raid non-stop, when your army is at home its being wasted. you should be trying to create a buffer zone around your capital making it difficult for anyone to invade your capital.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This work is an original guide from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.travianguide.com&#34;&gt;Travian Guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;#The Goal of this Roman Guide&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go from a single lone town of peasant farmers, to an active raider within a strong alliance. This Travian guide will attempt to take you through the first 10 days of your account, at which point you will be ready to found your second town. You should found your second village by the 14th day, or else your already well behind, and have made major errors in playing Travian and are already likely to become a farm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;#Who this Travian Roman Guide is for&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New players with the basic understanding of the interface and how game screens work that don’t want to be someones farm again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;#Introduction&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Travian Roman guide will not teach you how to become a top player (as I never manage that myself), but it will give you the basics to become a farmer instead of a farm.If you are currently a large players farm, you should probably restart your account because the farmer always wins in Travian. This guide focuses on Speed server, because I find all other servers of Travian far to slow and boring. In fact I often find speed server to slow once I run out of people in a reasonable range to farm. This guide requires a reasonable amount of play time to follow. However, reasonable in Travian terms is at least two hours a day everyday. If you can’t play your Travian account twice a day for an hour each day, then you will be unsuccessful and the most you can hope for is someone bigger protecting you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day1-2&lt;/strong&gt; Note your start date in your profile so you can track your on progress. Begin building your resource fields, focus on clay, then wood, then iron, and lastly crop. Building resource fields requires more clay than wood, more wood than iron, and very little food. Your objective will be to get 3′s for all clay and wood resources, 2 for iron (3 if Roman), and 2′s for food. I try to keep my food around 50-100 per hour until my resources are finished in a city because more just goes to waste, or has to get traded on the market.. Once you hit 3′s in wood and clay it is time to build a level 3 main building, a barracks, and a rally point, and a warehouse. Once you have two units trained you are ready to raid. Go to /www.traviantool.com/ and do a search for inactives around town. In your first few raids you’ll want to hit people with less than 10 population who are at least 3 days inactive because even 1 defender could slow you down. If your target is the square next to your village, you are in luck. His 3200 resources will soon pay for your first batch of soldiers. Raid this target over and over again until his resources are gone. Spend his resources on more troops and resources upgrades here and there. You may also need to expand your warehouse to hold your new found resources. Once the first farm runs out of resources, move on to the second best farm on your screen. Remember that these farms will tend to refill their resources after a 12 hour period. So, you should hit each of your farms again at the end of the day. Repeat this process over the next couple days until there are no easy resources left within 20 minutes of your capital.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day 4&lt;/strong&gt; At this point an experienced player will start noticing a real difference between Teuton and Roman. As Teuton your raiders are dirt cheap and you’ll start amassing them quickly. You will also be ready to hire a few scouts soon. Roman legionnaire are expensive and slow to train, even with the new found resources from farming they are hard to pay for. While the Teutonic army is rapidly approaching 100 Clubbies! At this point the guide starts to vary some depending on your race. I will follow the Teuton path from here as it is the most aggressive. With 75 club swingers you’ll be able to start raiding villages 2 at one time, and you’ll likely drain their complete stock of resources in 1 hit! This means your ready for bigger fish. I begin hitting any realm within 6 range of my own that is 3 days inactive. If the guy looks scary skip him until you have a scout you should quickly out pace anyone near you. It is important to avoid getting into any real fights. Your only goal in Travian should be to hit people who can’t defend themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Resources Note I don’t always build resource fields evenly. I often have more resources than I can spend on anything other than troops. So I will take short cuts on my clay or wood, because building time slows me down more than resource usage. As long as you sit at the computer and raid actively you should be able to afford any upgrades you want to buy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Caution:&lt;/strong&gt; If you have active farmers around you, they may see you as an easy farm. It is important to send your army on a 5 hour attack (10 hour total mission) before you log off for the day, and before you go to sleep at night. Your army is your main source of resources, if they die you will suffer a devastating setback. Think of your army as you would your resource fields. You don’t want to lose troops just as you wouldn’t want to lose resource fields!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day 6&lt;/strong&gt; If you raid actively you should be ready for a hero today, just in case any of your farms gets active on you. By this point you should have 150 clubbies, and level 5 resource fields. Your warehouse should always be able to hold 10 times your hourly production, but no more (so you can go to sleep without falling behind). Meanwhile your probably raiding 8-10 separate targets (more if you spend more time on Travian). When you log in for the morning, open your map screen, right click your targets, open in new tab all 10 of your targets. Go through and send just enough troops to empty out each target. If you can’t remember how many resources each raid target has, keep a text file of the number of troops to send to each target. If a target has 800 of each resource then send 800*&lt;sup&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;60&lt;/sub&gt;= 54 club swingers (or 800*&lt;sup&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;40&lt;/sub&gt;=80 Legionnaire). A target with 1200 of each resource would require 1200*&lt;sup&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;60&lt;/sub&gt;=80 club swingers. By this point if you didn’t start late in the game you should already be shopping around for a small wing of a large alliance to join. You should stand out from your neighbors, and you are ready to contact a big alliance near you and inform them of your successful start. A recruiter looking at your area will easily see that you are the largest town within 10 squares. You can also paste him or her your most successful farm reports so he can see you have quite a large army for your size. If you are not accepted into an alliance don’t be tempted to start your own, it is a clear sign of weakness. Also, do not join a farm alliance unless you can find one that appears larger than your threatening neighbors because it offers you nothing, and gets you put on a “farm list”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Caution:&lt;/strong&gt; Lone fast building players are often prime targets for veteran farmers. You won’t really be able to field a decent army, so just stick to your offense plan. Send your army out when your not playing so, under no circumstances should you lose any soldiers on defense or even let someone scout you with your army at home. You will cause them to fear you, which means they will see your existence as a threat to their own. Just let the farmer come in and take what he can get, yet don’t let him slow you down. Keep up the raiding, keep trying to find allies. You may soon out grow your over confident farmer. However, if you happen to load 4 minutes away from a serious player, like yourself, who has a large head start on you, then you may have to restart and try again. But. before you do, you should dump all your resources into training a pure defensive army and hero with as many walls as practical. You will have to build up for several days in a row which means you’ll have to hide them from him. By taking the time and store up a large force, you can wipe out one of his or her raiding forces. This can be especially true if you repeat the event or delete the account before he or she can recover lost resources from you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day8&lt;/strong&gt; It will be time to expand to a second city soon, slow down club production and start a residence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day10&lt;/strong&gt; If you make it to this point without being attacked, then it is getting less likely that anyone will attack you. By this point as Teuton I carry 50 spear fighters, and around 600 Clubbies. (In almost all games I get careless and lose 50-100 clubbies beating down my upstart neighbors. This should be avoided if possible as it costs you precious raiders. However, some newbies your size may carry 25-30000 resources with no armies to speak of. By using scouts on all active players before hitting you can make sure they are defenseless, but remember their defense may just be away. By this point in the game I farm the nearest 20-30 inactive players. I also usually have 1 or 2 farms my own size who either didn’t have army, or who had a very small army. I break my army up into groups of 50 and send them out to the nearest 12 targets. As the closer raiders come in, I send them back out again. I do this twice a day, so that I can have enough resources to build settlers, keep up building resource fields, and replacing lost clubbies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its time to expand! Army production takes a back seat for 12 hours while the expansion is underway. By the end of day 10 you should have your first expansion. If not you are slacking on your raiding efforts. Once you get large enough you’ll go weeks or months without using defense. However, right now you are extremely vulnerable. If you aren’t in an alliance yet, recontact the people you laid ground work with previously. Point out your drastic increase in population and second village because this will let them know you are a serious player. However, if you started late, you will probably have to go it alone for a while. This means you will have to found multiple villages before a decent alliance will take you seriously. Maintain friendly but not overly pestering contacts with smaller wings of big alliances. L.R. for example is a huge wing and certainly full, but L.R.2 will have fewer and smaller players, thus making them more receptive to new recruits. You’re goal should be to reach the minimum population or army requirements for the alliance you wish to join.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day11&lt;/strong&gt; You should make it to a level 10 forest resource by the end of today. From here the sky and a third village is the limit! Your second village should be starting an army, and begin raiding the villages near it so that it can support itself and stop draining your first town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t make it to a large alliance within two weeks because you’re under constant attack, then you have three choices:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Consider this round a practice run and learn about war and defense.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Found your second city well away from your farmer, preferably near a large collection farms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Restart your account and hope for better position.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Travian Tools</title>
      <link>http://www.travianguide.com/travian-tools</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.travianguide.com/travian-tools</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Travian web-based tool sites, offer many simple tools to make playing Travian easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.traviantoolbox.com/en/&#34;&gt;Travian Tool Box&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.traviantool.com/en-US/&#34;&gt;Travian Tool&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://itravtools.com/&#34;&gt;iTravtools&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of the tools are neat, but only a few are indispensable. My most frequent use of tool sites is to find good farms, or to get an overview on player distances in a war.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The full range of tools available from these sites differ slightly from site to sight, but here is a list of the tools from each site. From the toolbox I most often use the battle plan tool because its extremely helpful in assigning war targets. Tool sites often provide mapping tools as well, but dedicated map tools are much more powerful for mapping players.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;#Tool Box&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Troop Comparison&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Combat Simulator&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Distances and time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CR converter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Players Signatures&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Calculators&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Graphic packs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Map&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lists&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Battle Plan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Farms Search&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Statistics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;#Travian Tool&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From Travian Tool I most often use the inactives tool to find farms. Neighbors is also a decent tool, and the statistics are quite fun when your bored, but for statistics its best to use world analyzers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Statistics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Servers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alliances&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Players&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Villages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;#iTravi Tools&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best iTravi tool is it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://itravtools.com/travian-analyser/travian-inactive-player-around/&#34;&gt;inactive player&lt;/a&gt; finder. Give it a try!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teuton Guide</title>
      <link>http://www.travianguide.com/teuton-guide</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.travianguide.com/teuton-guide</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Specifics:
* Sufficient time needed for offensive play.
* Inexpensive troops may be produced fast, good at looting.
* For aggressive and experienced players.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Teuton guide will give you the basics of playing as an agressive looter. The Teutons have several important advantages that other players don&amp;rsquo;t share. They can train units faster than any other tribe. Their troops are inexpensive, and they carry extra loot. These 3 elements combine to make Teuton the strongest early raiders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While their troops aren&amp;rsquo;t quite as strong as Roman&amp;rsquo;s in the late game, the early game advantage in raiding can mean the Teuton player has a larger kingdom with more villages. Teutons excel at being the first to capture 15 crop villages. You can use a &lt;a href=&#34;travian-crop-finder&#34;&gt;Crop Finder&lt;/a&gt; to locate one early on in your game.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Travian Gual Guide</title>
      <link>http://www.travianguide.com/travian-gual-guide</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.travianguide.com/travian-gual-guide</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, you read my &lt;a href=&#34;travian-romadn-guide&#34;&gt;Travian Roman guide&lt;/a&gt;. You take full advantage of the club swingers fast movement, cheap cost, and quick production time to crush everything around you. However, that was last round, this round you got jealous over fast calvary, and lightning quick defenders, and chose to start as Gaul. Now how the heck do you survive against that Teuton punk next to you? If you were Teuton, you’d have his club swingers beat 3 to 1… but your stuck with Gaul so now what?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While farming is the most important aspect of Travian, it is even more important to farm as a Gaul. Your raiders aren’t cheap, and they aren’t as quick to produce, so you won’t be able to make 150 units on your first day of raiding like you could with club swingers. &lt;strong&gt;A Gaul player can get a heavy boost from Resource bonuses and NPC trade.&lt;/strong&gt; But, lets look at Gaul’s advantages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fast easy to produce defenders&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Double Cranny&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Traps&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So to start as Gaul you’ve got to rely on these three things. And make sure you raid only INACTIVE players. Rather than producing a barracks on your second day, hold off until the third day to give your neighbors a chance to quit the game and go inactive before you farm them. Make sure you have a level 8-10 cranny, and a level 1 trapper right out of new player protection. If you have stupid Teuton neighbors, they will send in 2-3 club swingers and get them trapped. You can then add another level to your traps, and produce 5-10 phalanx. By the time he comes back, you’ll smack his poor raiding force, and he will be sore. However, a good Teuton rival will first raid all the Romans, and Teutons, and not come for you until hes got enough numbers to ignore traps.  If you play actively your population should scare him off. but If it doesn’t he will raid you, and get his clubbies trapped, gain zero resources, and find you very annoying. Make sure you keep your phalanx safe from him, and use those double crannies so he always gets zero resources from you. Its VERY important not to give an inch, as you’ll be applying to a strong alliance soon, and stolen resources make you look weak. Instead you want the alliance leader to see your collection of phalanx and a string of worthless raids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Phalanx are poor raiders, they are great defenders, You should start making these as soon as your resources are level 4. 15-30 phalanx are plenty to clean out the inactives around you, and allow you to push for TT. These quick calvary are the fastest raiders in the game. Remember to be EXTREMELY careful, an active Roman with 4-5 legionnaire will ruin all your fun, even after you have TT, so make sure you only hit inactives.  Its crucial that you get into a good alliance soon, so push hard to collect 10-12 TT, and keep raiding with those phalanx. If your being hit by a Teuton, and haven’t made any friends yet, you should consider buying some gold to use NPC trades to create resources. set 1-2 market trades Wood for Food, then NPC food into Wood… you can make 20,000 resources easily, giving you the boost you need to produce settlers, or create more TT.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re being heavily pressured by a Teuton, TT are his worst fear, so protect them at all cost, once you have a TT hero, and 10 TT you can really hurt him by clipping his clubbies. 10 TT with a hero can massacre even large Teutonic armies at this point in the game almost no one has spear fighters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wipe your neighbors army and watch them come running for an alliance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By 8 days into the game you should have your second village going (preferably a 6 cropper) and you’re game should be moving along nicely. You’ll be pushing your way towards 50 TT and any Teutons around you, will hate you by now. Give the alliance you want to join a travilog of some of your hits, or just tell him to check your offense score. Good alliance leaders will be excited to find a Gaul with offense points and floored by your “skillz”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point push your traps to 50-60, this will make you invulnerable to roman and other Gaul players. If a Gaul your size tries to raid you, hes going to get his entire army trapped, and your phalanx are going to massacre those poor TT. If a roman tries to hit you… his legions are going to be hard pressed to beat your traps and your phalanx… but if a large pop Teuton tries to raid you… dodge them!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you can manage a top 500 start with a Gaul, your a serious committed player any alliance will be happy to have. Just realize, getting there with a slow to start faction is hard work. You have to do a lot of small raids using phalanx, and you’ll find swords slow and expensive compared to those clubbies you love. But, once you have 200 TT, and you start clearing clubbies 500 at a time, you’ll be happy you decided to play Gaul. If Gaul isn’t your thing, then read my Roman guide.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Army Production in a Large Empire</title>
      <link>http://www.travianguide.com/army-production-in-a-large-empire</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.travianguide.com/army-production-in-a-large-empire</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The goal of this Travian tips guide is to teach you intermediate players how to build massive armies often referred to as “hammers”. After the beginning phase of the game is over building huge armies is your primary goal. Your resource production will soon greatly out pace your need for resources., and I hope this article will give you some Travian Tips to accomplish that. However, there are still limiting factors on growth and army size that every large player must deal with. The first limitation most players face is that offense is very slow to travel over long distances. And, the attackers troops must all be produced from one village, while the defenders armies combine from many villages. However, it is very easy to use villages as storage for your troops. Because of the nature of offense in Travian combined with the power and expense of blacksmiths and armories, it is the most efficient strategy to produce army in only a handful of specialized villages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By focusing your army production in a handful of key cities you can greatly increase the efficiency of your empire. Focusing your armies is a key Travian tip. You will only need blacksmiths and armories in 2 or 3 key cities instead of 20 or more. You will also not have a need for a level 20 barracks or stable outside of these cities. Although, many players become bored late in the game and max out all their buildings for “population”. Your capital should always be the site of your main offensive army, and if you plan to be a very large player, you should found a 15 crop capital with at least 100% food oasis. You can find such a village with crop tools from our tools section. It is very important that your Capital city produce 3 senators and not be used for settler production. These Senators will be the foundation of your mid game assault force. They will devastate an enemy city’s loyalty in one attack (and make Big parties more effective). This tactic takes care to execute as conquering senators disappear permanently when the target city reaches 0 loyalty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only drawback to this strategy is that you must constantly ship resources from your satellite villages to your production centers. A plus account makes this task easier, especially for Roman players who have great difficulty sending out all their resources without level 19 trade offices. Also, it becomes more difficult to raid from villages that have no army of their own. However, as an empire reaches a large size, raiding small targets becomes less and less productive, and most of the action switches to large hits from your key cities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While it may seem easier to produce defenders in every city. One of my best Travian Tips tells you it is by far more effective to produce defenders in 1 or 2 key defense cities that posses level 20 armories and upgrades for each defensive unit. These defenders can then be “passed out” to other cities to reduce the strain on your crop supplies and add greater security to your empire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Placement of your “key” production cities can be very important. Your Capital should become the focal point and center of your empire as it is the source of all of your power and influence. Centrally located defense cities also make it easier to send defenses out to the farthest reaches of your empire more quickly. However, a secondary attacking village may be located at the edges of an empire to extend influence and farming range.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last and most important specialized city which many players often neglect is a scouting village. One village can easily hold 1500 scouts (double for Tuetons). This village will ensure that you can always scout any enemy no matter how large.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Travian Analyzers</title>
      <link>http://www.travianguide.com/travian-analyzers</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.travianguide.com/travian-analyzers</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Travian analyzers are used to track population growth, conquers, rank movements, and much more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://travianstats.de/&#34;&gt;Travian Stats&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://travian.ws/&#34;&gt;Travian WS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While many players have seen these tools, few realize the value they serve to yourself and to an alliance leader. The analyzer’s main use for a recruiter is to determine whether a prospective recruit just had a rough start, or if he’s just a dead weight farm looking for protection. Analyzers are great for checking on the activity of potential farms, inactives are really obvious even if they log in once in a while, you’ll be able to see they almost never build! The TSU analyzer also has a poor man’s crop finder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are an alliance leader, you can punch in your alliance into the analyzer and get an overview of population growth and events for your entire alliance. You will quickly see why your top players are at the top, and those annoying inactive players are at the bottom… they simply don’t click on things. The analyzer allows you to go through someone’s history and see first hand just how inactive they were. When you boot someone, you’ll know you aren’t missing out on decent players.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another useful aspect of the analyzer is to check up on other alliances that are at war. Pull up both alliances and check for red that will indictate players who have died recently. You can also flip to the events tab, and see if there have been any conquers. The analyzer will teach you that most wars in Travian are Cold wars with little real action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While your in the events tab, you’ll see that Great players expand in a predictable time frame. 4-7 days after they start, a great player has 2 villages, within 12 days they have 3! Meahwhile, average players take 10-12 days for the second village and 15-16 for 3. Weak players, farms, will often go 21-30 days before founding their second village! If someone wants to join your alliance simply flip to events, if they haven’t made their second village in less than 12 days, they are a waste of your energy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last feature of the TSU analyzer is its “Crop View”. While not sufficient for finding all croppers in a game, it can be used to keep track of the croppers around your villages, so you can find where the heavy hitters are, and also see if any near by croppers can be taken.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Travian Maps</title>
      <link>http://www.travianguide.com/travian-maps</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.travianguide.com/travian-maps</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are many maps of Travian, and I will not attempt to make a comprehensive list of mapping sites. Instead I will simply give you links to a couple of my favorite map tools. Most are a bit hard to use at first, as they are often case sensitive for no reason. But once you get the hang of them, they are a great when organizing alliance wings. or when deciding where to found new villages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://travmap.shishnet.org/&#34;&gt;Shishnet’s Travmap&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.travianmap.nl/&#34;&gt;TravianMap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally, I prefer Travian Map because it has more features, however, it is harder to use. Travian Map will zoom in easily (although not out). It will allow you to hover over a dot to find out who that dot is, and It has several advanced display features I never bother with. Yet, alliance names are case sensitive so it is often very difficult to get all the alliances on the page, and its &lt;strong&gt;extremely&lt;/strong&gt; difficult to find your server in the drop down lists of servers. This drop down problem is a huge weakness to the site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Travian map is a more powerful map, its interface weaknesses cause it to take longer to use, so when I want a quick and easy map, I visit Shishnet’s Travimap. Its lacking in the advanced features, but if you want a nice picture of your friends or enemies this map will take care of you.n by killing their solders, you can only win by killing their food, because food income per hour is the limiting factor on a wonder, not the number of soldiers it has. Soldiers almost always out number the amount of food the care givers can supply. Even if you can’t kill thier food, you can force them to send out mass defense requests which consumes tons of food. The more they have to send to the same account the better.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Travian Crop Finder</title>
      <link>http://www.travianguide.com/travian-crop-finder</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.travianguide.com/travian-crop-finder</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I think you guys know what to do from here. A cropper, or high crop village is a must have for any successful Travian Empire. A 9 crop village gives you the ability to build a semi-large raiding force. But, the 15 crop village is ideal for a massive army. The top players will all aquire 15 crop villages within their first 4 villages. So, it may be difficult to find one at first. But, don&amp;rsquo;t give up. It&amp;rsquo;s possible to conquer these later on if you missed your chance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, you’ve found out what a “cropper” is, a village with more than 6 crop fields, and you realize you need one to support a huge army. But, how do you locate one? There are so many hexes and it takes forever to click on them all. The answer is simple. You use a crop finder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You could search hex by hex with your mouse, as I did to find my first cropper, but this takes hours, and your liable to miss villages right under your nose! The searching for croppers is a massive disappointment in The Travian interface, that makes the game incredibly hard to play. So, instead of cramping our sore wrists, we use automated tools to give us the information we need. There are many different types of crop finders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the best &lt;a href=&#34;http://croppers.travibot.com/&#34;&gt;Travian Crop Finder&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Travian Beyond</title>
      <link>http://www.travianguide.com/travian-beyond</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.travianguide.com/travian-beyond</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Travian Beyond is a &lt;a href=&#34;http://userscripts-mirror.org/scripts/show/15943&#34;&gt;Greasemonkey script&lt;/a&gt; that improves the interface of the game. It has more than
&lt;strong&gt;1 million&lt;/strong&gt; installs. The script does not send any commands to the server, and does not cheat for you. All the script does is fix several very annoying bugs and short comings in the user interface. For example, 99% of the time you attack, you want to raid. So, raid should be the default option. However, Travian’s inactive programmers have left “reinforce” as the default option. This flaw, forces an active player to create hundreds of extra clicks every single day. Travian beyond fixes this by setting the default option to raid rather than reinforce. Use Travian Beyond to conduct one farm run, and you’ll never understand why the programmers of Travian don’t fix this interface bug.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Travian Beyond also has several other key features. It gives you access to the “note pad” from the main overview screen, as well as showing you graphically what level all your buildings and resource fields are without forcing you to click or hover on them. Beyond also has many, links built into it that make the game more fun. Have you ever wondered why the combat simulator is so hard to get to? Or why you have to make so many clicks to get to your alliance overview? How about trading, raiding, or the rally point… all of these things are 1 click away from the overview screen with Travian beyond. While multihunter will tell you creating a webpage of links is cheating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also includes a battle analyzer, however it is not as powerful as the battle analyzer made by travilog. So you’ll want to use both scripts when playing Travian. The newest version is most likely not detactable by MH because the images are now all grabbed from a lycos server, but the old version did get many people in trouble. To my knowledge no one was banned for it, but that could change in the future. Travian beyond is used by almost all of the game’s top players, and no world wonder holder would ever leave home without it, simply because it makes transfering resources take fewer clicks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Travian Beyond does not farm for you, and it does not build for you, so we don’t think its cheating. Its simply using an unmodified firefox to access the game. The script does not send anything to the game, nor automate any actions. It does not tax the server in anyway. In fact its main purpose was to repair Interface problems that the Travian programmers are too lazy to fix. In most player’s opinion Travian beyond should be built into the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“§5 Use of externals&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The use of scripts or bots which automate actions (such as building upgrades, building troops, sending troops, trading, developing researches, attacking alerts or crop finders) or modify the game interface (for example, grease monkey scripts) are against the rules. The game must be played with an unmodified internet browser. All scripts which excessively tax the server are also forbidden.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything Travian Beyond does is local to your computer, and any software you run or write on your own computer is your business, not triers. No one can dictate which software you install or run on your machine, only wither or not you use a bot to interact with their server. So long as you do nothing to harm the game, you’ve done nothing wrong. Further reading below. That being said past users of the script have been banned so use it at your own risk. It is considered cheating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Download &lt;a href=&#34;http://userscripts-mirror.org/scripts/show/15943&#34;&gt;Travian Beyond&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alliance Founder Leaves</title>
      <link>http://www.travianguide.com/alliance-founder-leaves</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.travianguide.com/alliance-founder-leaves</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, you started a Travian alliance and you want to quit? So, you need to know what happens when the alliance founder leaves the alliance. Maybe your the co-leader, and you want to bump off the alliance founder. Maybe you just want to quit the alliance and move to the World Wonder meta-alliance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The boys and I have done some testing, and this is how it works:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The alliance founder may be special because he holds the embassy, and started with all the privileges, but the founder is no different from any other account in the guild. If you give “assign position” to another player, he can use those rights to remove your privileges, or even kick you from the alliance you have founded! So, be very careful giving rights out. Reserve “assign position” for yourself. No one else should need this, unless of course you want to leave, or become inactive. If the founder of the alliance deletes, or quits, nothing happens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s right if you quit, no one will even notice. Just make sure you gave “assign position” to someone else in the guild, because then they will have full control over every aspect of the guild. If the founder quit and gave no one “assign position” well then you’re all out of luck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The number of players an alliance can hold is based on the &lt;strong&gt;largest&lt;/strong&gt; embassy in the group. This embassy need not be the founder’s! If you get tired of building the embassy, make someone else do it. Delegate the task to a good Teuton player who can afford it. As long as he doesn’t have “assign position” he has no extra power except that he can destroy the embassy, and force you to rebuild it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your embassy is catapulted, you do not lose any players. You simply can’t add new players until you rebuild it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Destroy a World Wonder</title>
      <link>http://www.travianguide.com/how-to-destroy-a-world-wonder</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.travianguide.com/how-to-destroy-a-world-wonder</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“I have a big alliance I will attack them until they are all dead. Then I will attack them more!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That will not get you far. If the enemy is over 5 hours away, It takes far to long to kill even 1 account. By the time you’ve gotten even 1 kill, the game will be long over. C.H spent 2 solid months trying to kill my single account last round at a range of 6 hours, and by the reset they had managed to only dent my population. If you want to prevent  someone from winning, and your serious about it, there are only a few paths:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Build hammers with 5000+ level 20 catapults and wait for your enemy to go for a win, when they do you strike their WW, with your entire army. If you have just enough men, you’ll set them back several levels.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Strike the main supporters. Break their will to play Travian by conquering outliers. This only works if your lucky enough to be close to the enemy. If you can get even 1 player to give up the game without having to kill him, you’ve damaged their chance. Most alliances carry many high pop unimportant players that they will use as buffers. The alliance will happily let you eat your fill of conquers to keep you busy on unimportant players while the real shakers win the race.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Strike at the main food providers. There are many 15 croppers, but a non capital 15 isn’t worth that much at all. Good WW players clear out their capital army so it produces 200,000 crops per hour. These offensless players become the backbone of feeding the world wonder. Take out those crop fields, and the food grinds to a halt, You can also target TO’s and Market places from key towns.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Strike the support villages that are being used to pool reserve food. Last round 1 player K00jo managed to get off hundreds of cata waves simply by always using equal fakes on all villages each target was always hit with 5 waves… 24 would be faked, 1 would be real… half the time all 25 would be fake. He’d hit once, go for my crop fields and main building, and then switch, sometimes to a different target.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You must hit them like this every single day, Twice per day. The more players you have that can do this, the better your odds, if they can predict any attack and kill the clearing army, the fight is over and you’ve lost. In the end K00jo lost last round, because I clipped all his catapults so many times, he simply ran out of will to build more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You cannot win by killing their solders, you can only win by killing their food, because food income per hour is the limiting factor on a wonder, not the number of soldiers it has. Soldiers almost always out number the amount of food the care givers can supply. Even if you can’t kill thier food, you can force them to send out mass defense requests which consumes tons of food. The more they have to send to the same account the better.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Travian Bots</title>
      <link>http://www.travianguide.com/travian-bots</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.travianguide.com/travian-bots</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are 3 popular Travian bots. Each bot will fully automate your account. Bots are prohibited by Travian &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.travian.us/index.php#spielregeln&#34;&gt;rules&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;§1.7 The use of scripts or bots which automate actions or modify the game interface are against the rules. The game must be played with an unmodified internet browser.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using these bots will likely get your accounts banned from the server. Unlike &lt;a href=&#34;travian-beyond&#34;&gt;Travian Beyond&lt;/a&gt;, Travian Bots are detectable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The top three bots for Travian are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://travibot.com/en/&#34;&gt;Travibot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.traviantactics.com/download.php&#34;&gt;Travian Tactics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.travianbot.com/&#34;&gt;TravianBot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thousands of players are using these tools to win top positions. But, using these risk getting your account deleted.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free Travian Gold</title>
      <link>http://www.travianguide.com/free-travian-gold</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.travianguide.com/free-travian-gold</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Do you want some Travian free gold? Well I know how to get it!  Let Travian make it for you. Yes, you can get Travian gold for free. All you have to do is your Travian referral link when you post in other games. Travian gets millions of visitors every month, but many folks in other games won&amp;rsquo;t know it exists. When someone uses your links, you’ll get gold. Every time someone signs up for a Travian server using your referral link and plays to 75 population you get 20 gold!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Travian Multihunter</title>
      <link>http://www.travianguide.com/travian-multihunter</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.travianguide.com/travian-multihunter</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So how does Travian multihunter work? The first thing a person learns when they contact Travian multihunter is that its EXTREMELY difficult for Travain multihunter to help you. And, that a smart person always contacts Multihunter2 as multihunter1 is always too busy. A MH needs an exact link to the game screen in question before they can see other people’s accounts. Simply giving them the account name isn’t enough. What this means for cheaters, is even people who blab about scripting and password sharing usually get away with it because MH simply doesn’t have good automated tools for detecting messages with people’s passwords in them. Simple fix: Check for the users password from the user’s table of the database before every IGM is sent. If any person on any Travian server EVER sends an IGM with their password in it, the game can ban them automatically no human interaction needed. If your going to password share, do it on Instant messenger. The fact that Travian allows you to share your password via IGM is a security failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also the game automatically deletes all the evidence of every game event every week. So someone cheats for the first couple of weeks and then stops, the evidence will be cleaned by the game in a very short time frame. This also bites you in the ass when someone sends you threatening messages. If you don’t report them to MH before the message deletes, Travian multihunter WILL NOT HELP YOU.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tech side of catching cheaters is fairly straight forward. Any web game has two main methods of cheat detection. Internet Protocol (IP) address, and cookie/session key. Every machine on the Internet has an IP address, when you play two accounts from the same network, like from a college dorm, your IP will match another user. Travian has a feature called pc-sharing that allows people who share the same IP to play travian. Basically, anyone with a matching IP who isn’t on the pc sharing list is on the short list for a ban. Those who cheat from college dorm rooms and other public networks often get away with it for longer. Once MH finds a matching IP they look at account activity. If the two accounts work closely together, are never online at the same second, and  seem to communicate without IGM, they are highly likely to be banned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Travian session cookies is the second method travian multihunter use to catch cheaters. Your browser records a session for you each time you log in. If you log in to someone elses account with a cookie from another account, you are automatically flagged as a cheat.  So, clear your cookies right? Wrong! A suspect cheater who always has no cookie or state information on every connection will often be scrutinized extra hard as a cheat. The most affective way to run 3 accounts is to use 1 browser for each account. That way you have nice clean sessions for each account you play. You just have to make sure you don’t forget which browser is which.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hiding your IP address is simple its called a public proxy, google will give you several website that will display hundreds of proxies. However, a proxy is slow, and seriously makes travian less fun, as you can’t split waves from a proxy server. To stop this Travian multihunter can simply blacklist all public proxies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you being farmed by a cheater with the auto farm script? Stay tuned for a post on autofarm. How it works, why people don’t get caught, and how to get someone caught!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Village Placement Tricks</title>
      <link>http://www.travianguide.com/village-placement-tricks</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.travianguide.com/village-placement-tricks</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, you’re an active raider 10 days into the game and ready to found your second village. But, where to put it? This guide will cover the criteria for village placement.This guide is intended for new players who haven’t much experience with founding villages, but may also be useful to experienced players who haven’t put much thought into where they place villages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The basic assumption of this guide is that you are in a major alliance. This means that no major alliance members should farm you without causing a diplomatic incident. If you are a lone player, the guide should still be helpful, but you are asking to get farmed or even conquered at any time. Therefor unallied players should focus heavily on defense. The alliance is a lot like organized crime because the alliance offer you protection, and you offer them troops. Few successful players make it long without joining a big alliance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;#Village founding options&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1.Directly next to your capital&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;.Relatively close to your capital (one screen away)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Semi-close such as within 3 screens&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extremely far away&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Option 1 is probably most common because it allows for quick transport of resources and troops to the new village. This makes for ideal protection of new villages, as well as a great place to store extra offense troops from your capital because they can be quickly recalled for attacks. However, this approach has several drawbacks which most don’t consider. This selection does nothing to increase your raiding range. It also means you won’t get extra oasis for your new town. Also remember that most players move their capital early on to a large crop village to support a larger army. Which means these villages will end up not being as close to defensive troops as you may like late in the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Option 2 is my primary choice for all new villages including my second village. I enjoy having a raiding force in each new town and the new village can be planted directly next to good farms. I also maintain more oasis throughout the game with this strategy. Although, some may consider this option too risky because you tend to encroach on others more frequently and have a longer period for reinforcements and supply. I have found that my satellite villages rarely fall under serious attack, and when they do the attacks come from far enough away that it is very easy to defend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Option 3 Is often usd to found 9 and 15 crop villages as you don’t have much choice as thier location. Or, this option can be used to increase the distance between your empire and a farmer. Sometimes this option can be helpful if you want to place a city near larger allies for protection or to protect a smaller ally. It can also be useful to leap frog away from allies to expand your raiding range. Large alliances create huge dead zones where unallied farms never survive. This makes the game very boring for a farmer, and placing your villages away from the main cluster can improve your resource gathering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Option 4 is usually a last ditch effort to get free of a farmer after option 3 fails to elude him. It is similar to starting your account over, but it uses your capital as a leg up. I don’t believe many serious players found resource clusters in the void around the outside of the game as troop transport times are wicked. But, this can be a viable choice for new players looking for some peaceful simcity play. Option 4 can also be used by members of large alliances to find “dead zones” in their quadrant where no allies exist. By moving your empire to the heart of a dead zone it will make for a very active and aggressive game. To find such zones, create a list of all the alliances allied to your own alliance and input them into a Travian map tool such as those in the map tools section.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By following Option 2 your empire expands much like a command and conquer base that will eventually stretch far and wide in all four directions. I try to keep all of my border towns within 2 hours of my &lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;15&lt;/sub&gt; crop capital because your only real offense will come from that town. With each new town you found, try to plant it right next to your best farm, and within range of at least 2 oasis. Also, you’ll want to give your allies some space because sharing farms and oasis is always a bummer. When selecting villages you want to take special care to avoid large aggressive players. While many players are content to ignore another large player 2 screens away, if you found a village within sight of their capital you may just start a war that will be very costly. Of course if you have your eye on some soon to be farms… a perfect way to get a foot hold near them is to found a village there. Most players will be afraid of players much larger than themselves, so they will ignore your town despite your inability to defend it. By the time they realize you are about to conquer all their villages you have 2 senators with in 15 minutes of their entire empire.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>