<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tools on Travian Guide</title>
    <link>https://www.travianguide.com/categories/tools/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tools on Travian Guide</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.travianguide.com/categories/tools/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Travian Tools</title>
      <link>https://www.travianguide.com/travian-tools</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.travianguide.com/travian-tools</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Travian web-based tool sites, offer many simple tools to make playing Travian easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.traviantoolbox.com/en/&#34;&gt;Travian Tool Box&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.traviantool.com/en-US/&#34;&gt;Travian Tool&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://itravtools.com/&#34;&gt;iTravtools&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of the tools are neat, but only a few are indispensable. My most frequent use of tool sites is to find good farms, or to get an overview on player distances in a war.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The full range of tools available from these sites differ slightly from site to sight, but here is a list of the tools from each site. From the toolbox I most often use the battle plan tool because its extremely helpful in assigning war targets. Tool sites often provide mapping tools as well, but dedicated map tools are much more powerful for mapping players.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;#Tool Box&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Troop Comparison&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Combat Simulator&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Distances and time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CR converter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Players Signatures&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Calculators&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Graphic packs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Map&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lists&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Battle Plan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Farms Search&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Statistics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;#Travian Tool&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From Travian Tool I most often use the inactives tool to find farms. Neighbors is also a decent tool, and the statistics are quite fun when your bored, but for statistics its best to use world analyzers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Statistics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Servers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alliances&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Players&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Villages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;#iTravi Tools&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best iTravi tool is it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://itravtools.com/travian-analyser/travian-inactive-player-around/&#34;&gt;inactive player&lt;/a&gt; finder. Give it a try!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Travian Analyzers</title>
      <link>https://www.travianguide.com/travian-analyzers</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.travianguide.com/travian-analyzers</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Travian analyzers are used to track population growth, conquers, rank movements, and much more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://travianstats.de/&#34;&gt;Travian Stats&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://travian.ws/&#34;&gt;Travian WS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While many players have seen these tools, few realize the value they serve to yourself and to an alliance leader. The analyzer’s main use for a recruiter is to determine whether a prospective recruit just had a rough start, or if he’s just a dead weight farm looking for protection. Analyzers are great for checking on the activity of potential farms, inactives are really obvious even if they log in once in a while, you’ll be able to see they almost never build! The TSU analyzer also has a poor man’s crop finder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are an alliance leader, you can punch in your alliance into the analyzer and get an overview of population growth and events for your entire alliance. You will quickly see why your top players are at the top, and those annoying inactive players are at the bottom… they simply don’t click on things. The analyzer allows you to go through someone’s history and see first hand just how inactive they were. When you boot someone, you’ll know you aren’t missing out on decent players.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another useful aspect of the analyzer is to check up on other alliances that are at war. Pull up both alliances and check for red that will indictate players who have died recently. You can also flip to the events tab, and see if there have been any conquers. The analyzer will teach you that most wars in Travian are Cold wars with little real action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While your in the events tab, you’ll see that Great players expand in a predictable time frame. 4-7 days after they start, a great player has 2 villages, within 12 days they have 3! Meahwhile, average players take 10-12 days for the second village and 15-16 for 3. Weak players, farms, will often go 21-30 days before founding their second village! If someone wants to join your alliance simply flip to events, if they haven’t made their second village in less than 12 days, they are a waste of your energy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last feature of the TSU analyzer is its “Crop View”. While not sufficient for finding all croppers in a game, it can be used to keep track of the croppers around your villages, so you can find where the heavy hitters are, and also see if any near by croppers can be taken.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Travian Maps</title>
      <link>https://www.travianguide.com/travian-maps</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.travianguide.com/travian-maps</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are many maps of Travian, and I will not attempt to make a comprehensive list of mapping sites. Instead I will simply give you links to a couple of my favorite map tools. Most are a bit hard to use at first, as they are often case sensitive for no reason. But once you get the hang of them, they are a great when organizing alliance wings. or when deciding where to found new villages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://travmap.shishnet.org/&#34;&gt;Shishnet’s Travmap&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.travianmap.nl/&#34;&gt;TravianMap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally, I prefer Travian Map because it has more features, however, it is harder to use. Travian Map will zoom in easily (although not out). It will allow you to hover over a dot to find out who that dot is, and It has several advanced display features I never bother with. Yet, alliance names are case sensitive so it is often very difficult to get all the alliances on the page, and its &lt;strong&gt;extremely&lt;/strong&gt; difficult to find your server in the drop down lists of servers. This drop down problem is a huge weakness to the site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Travian map is a more powerful map, its interface weaknesses cause it to take longer to use, so when I want a quick and easy map, I visit Shishnet’s Travimap. Its lacking in the advanced features, but if you want a nice picture of your friends or enemies this map will take care of you.n by killing their solders, you can only win by killing their food, because food income per hour is the limiting factor on a wonder, not the number of soldiers it has. Soldiers almost always out number the amount of food the care givers can supply. Even if you can’t kill thier food, you can force them to send out mass defense requests which consumes tons of food. The more they have to send to the same account the better.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Travian Crop Finder</title>
      <link>https://www.travianguide.com/travian-crop-finder</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.travianguide.com/travian-crop-finder</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I think you guys know what to do from here. A cropper, or high crop village is a must have for any successful Travian Empire. A 9 crop village gives you the ability to build a semi-large raiding force. But, the 15 crop village is ideal for a massive army. The top players will all aquire 15 crop villages within their first 4 villages. So, it may be difficult to find one at first. But, don&amp;rsquo;t give up. It&amp;rsquo;s possible to conquer these later on if you missed your chance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, you’ve found out what a “cropper” is, a village with more than 6 crop fields, and you realize you need one to support a huge army. But, how do you locate one? There are so many hexes and it takes forever to click on them all. The answer is simple. You use a crop finder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You could search hex by hex with your mouse, as I did to find my first cropper, but this takes hours, and your liable to miss villages right under your nose! The searching for croppers is a massive disappointment in The Travian interface, that makes the game incredibly hard to play. So, instead of cramping our sore wrists, we use automated tools to give us the information we need. There are many different types of crop finders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the best &lt;a href=&#34;http://croppers.travibot.com/&#34;&gt;Travian Crop Finder&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>